# **Richard Hughes**

Over the last few years, I've developed a passion for supporting those around me through my pursuit of unique, voluntary experiences with engaging challenges. Currently, I am studying at the University of Chester to build a career with my passion in Computer Science. I hope to find part-time work to support this, and further develop my skills in a professional environment.

# **Work Experience**

## **Shop Assistant - Debra Charity Store, Bispham**

Apr 2022 to Sep 2023

- Testing electronics for their usability, before pricing and displaying them.
- Photographing and publishing rare items on ecommerce sites for higher profits than if they were sold in-store.
- Assessing the quality of new donations, deciding which items are suitable to resell.
- Rearranging the in-store displays to engage new and returning customers.
- Pricing items by following the original price tag, online research, or looking at similar items in the store.
- Serving customers at the counter, providing a positive experience and addressing queries.
- Working in a team, solving problems based on the task priority and strengths of the team members.
- Adapting to a variety of tasks, many of which were taught under short notice, requiring me to learn quickly.

## **Volunteer - Blackpool Tiggers**

Jul 2021 to Jul 2022

- Caring for children of various ages while their parents are away; including providing entertainment, comfort, and safety.
- Developed communication skills for neurodivergent individuals through active listening, as well attentiveness to non-verbal signals and mindfulness of their individual needs before responding.
- ❖ Demonstrating trampoline moves for the children, giving praise and feedback for improvement.
- Adapting to the needs of each child to create a positive environment for them.

# **Education and Qualifications**

#### **University of Chester (BSc Hons - Computer Science)**

Sep 2023 to Present

- Developed a first-class Java application for sorting and analysing song collections.
- Designed and developed a first-class Microsoft SQL Server database with data entries.
- Designed a first-class mobile app user interface.
- Completed modules in cybersecurity, web development, mathematics and more.
- Proficient in Microsoft Office, Google Workspace and various operating systems.

#### Blackpool Sixth Form (A-Level & BTEC)

Sep 2021 to Jul 2023

- **❖** Computer Science: D
- **Business (Double):** Double Distinction

## **Hodgson Academy (GCSE 9-1)**

Sep 2016 to May 2021

- ❖ Grade 5s in English Language, Religious Studies, Business.
- Grade 6s in English Literature, Mathematics, Combined Science (Double), Computer Science, Geography.